sheridaninstitute.ca 2019-04-30

# Sheridan College

Sheridan College is committed to safeguarding the personal information of its website users as per its legislative requirements under the [Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (FIPPA)](https://www.sheridancollege.ca/about/administration-and-governance/legal-counsel/information-access-and-privacy/fippa).  Sheridan College will only use this information internally and will use all available means to protect the information it collects.

Below you will find information related to Sheridan’s strategies for protecting personal information and individual privacy while individuals are using www.sheridancollege.ca.   

## How does Sheridan College use technology to collect information through the Sites?

Sheridan College  collects anonymous information about site users which can include a user’s browser type, type of computer operating system, and the domain name of the website from which the user linked to the Sites. This information is collected for internal use, such as to measure website analytics, enhance website security, to detect broad demographic trends, to assist Sheridan College in providing content tailored to a user’s interests and to otherwise enhance the user experience on the Sites.

Sheridan may use a “cookie” or similar technology to assist us to customize the Sites. A “cookie” is a data file that a website sends to a user’s computer while that user is viewing the site. These data files include information that allows a website to remember information that will make that user’s use of the website more efficient and helpful Cookies do not damage computer systems or files, and only the website that transferred a particular cookie to you can read, modify or delete such cookie.  The use of cookies does not provide access to a computer’s hard drives, stored files or content, or any other locally stored information.

The way cookies are managed on a computer can be tailored to suit individual requirements.  A browser can be set to detect and reject cookies, to accept cookies from all sites, or to provide a prompt whenever a site wants to send a cookie. Individual browser “help” files can be consulted for guidance on how to set cookie preferences.  It is important to note however, that some web content may become unavailable if cookie preferences are changed.  Please see below for more information on opting out of cookies. 

## Opt-Out Process

To opt-out of Internet-based advertising, you can choose to:

• Set your browser to decline third party cookies.

• Delete the advertiser’s cookie each time you get it.

• Make use of [Ad Choices](https://youradchoices.ca/) cookie management processes

Please note that cookies are specific to your browser and computer. If you change browsers and/or computers, your settings will not carry over.

Opting-out does not mean you will no longer receive advertisements. It does mean that Sheridan College or its related websites from which you opted out will no longer customize ads based on your interests and web usage patterns using cookie-based technology.

## Industry Partner Online Behavioural Advertising / Targeted Advertising

Sheridan College engages in Online Behavioural Advertising (OBA) through www.sheridancollege.ca and Sheridan College makes use of industry partner solutions to engage in OBA. 

As you browse www.sheridancollege.ca, cookies will be placed on your computer. Cookies help personalize and maximize your online experience. The cookie has a unique identifier assigned to the device, but does not alone contain information about you personally. Sheridan College treats all of this information as your personal information to ensure it is properly protected.

Targeted ads displayed to you are based on the activity associated with the cookieID during your visit to www.sheridancollege.ca.

When showing you tailored ads, we do not associate an identifier from cookies (or similar technologies) with sensitive categories such as those based on race, religion or health. Sheridan College websites are not intended for use directly by children under 13 years of age. 

### Ad Networks and Anonymous Information 

We may have relationships with third party service providers known as Ad Networks to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet. Using cookies and similar technologies (such as “pixel tags”, “web beacons”, “clear GIFs”), Ad Networks collect anonymous information about your visits to our Sites and other websites in order to deliver advertisements that may be of particular interest to you. This process does not involve the collection of any personal information. For example, the Ad Networks do not know your name, phone number, address or email address and we do not share any personal information about you with these Ad Networks.

In connection with these Ad Networks, we adhere to the “Canadian Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioural Advertising”. These Principles were developed by the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada, a consortium of leading Canadian advertising and marketing associations, with the aim of applying consumer-friendly standards to online behavioural advertising across the World Wide Web.

To find out more about how Ad Networks manage the privacy of information in conjunction with delivering advertisements online, and how to opt-out of information collection by these Ad Networks, you can view websites such as: [http://www.youradchoices.ca ](http://www.youradchoices.ca/)and [http://www.networkadvertising.org ](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). We do not operate or control these websites, and we are not responsible for the opt-out choices available there.

### Third Party Service Providers

We use third party service providers to help administer our interest-based advertising systems. We require that these third party service providers protect the information they use on our behalf, including for online behavioural advertising and not to use it for any other purpose.

Sheridan College will only use information collected for the internal purposes listed here and will use all resources available to ensure that personal information is maintained securely.  Sheridan College will not sell, rent, exchange, or disclose your information for any reason unless there is a legal requirement to do so.

## User Generated Content

From time to time, we may receive content from consumers as part of contests, promotions and other functions of our Sites (“User Generated Content” or “UGC”). Any UGC you submit may be publicly displayed, including on our Sites, and is subject to any terms and conditions communicated to you as part of the submission process. 

Please remember that any information you disclose in connection with a UGC submission may become public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal, financial or other information in a submission. Sheridan College cannot prevent such information from being used in a manner that may violate this Privacy Statement, the law or your personal privacy and safety and Sheridan College is not responsible for the results of such postings.

## Contact Information

For more information on privacy at Sheridan, please review our [Privacy Policy](https://policy.sheridanc.on.ca/dotNet/documents/?docid=1009&ppublic=true) or contact [privacy@sheridancollege.ca](mailto:privacy@sheridancollege.ca).
